export const factData = [
  {
    id: 0,
    question: "Who am I?",
    answer:
      "A curious Fabiszewski who in his late-30s decided to get into web develpoment. This is one of my more thorough projects. I hope to learn from others here; the stories of Fabiszewskis and all spelling variations.",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "How to pronounce?",
    answer:
      "We lazily say Fa (like 'apple') buh-shehs-kee. But I've always heard it's closer to Fah-bi-chev-skee.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "What does it mean?",
    answer:
      "Though I've heard '-ewski' seems to mean of a certain place (Habitational Surname), according to Polish linguist and etymologist Kazimierz Rymut, the surname Fabiszewski is a patronymic surname derived from the given name Fabian. The ancient name historically respresents bean (Fava species) growers in the Roman Empire and it's spread through Europe. My uncle has proposed we may have very well been property of a landlord Fabian.",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "From where in Poland, exactly?",
    answer:
      "Bryon Fabiseski did his homework and got back to the 1700s in Mochowo; most families I was able to trace back to Poland have origins in a 50 mile radius of Mochowo, as well.",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "When did we arrive?",
    answer:
      "Post Civil-War 1800s for most families. I'd love to hear more dates. It looks like my Jan (later John) Fabiszewski possibly of Albert (Adelbertus/George) came over between 1880 and 1891.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "How many of us are there?",
    answer:
      "Most of the numbers I find likely consist of repeats and people no longer with us. The best I can do is 191 in the 2010 census. Seems in the range I'd expect.",
  },

  {
    id: 6,
    question: "Where do most of us live?",
    answer:
      "It looks like New York at somewhere around 133 (I'm not too sure about numbers like this), followed by Pennsylvania and New Jersey. Ancestry says: In 1920 there were 7 Fabiszewski families living in Wisconsin. This was about 24% of all the recorded Fabiszewski's in USA (the highest). I'm in Texas. None here, until recently, as far as I know.",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Who's the oldest living member?",
    answer: "I need submissions for this one, but I'm curious",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "Who was that Major?",
    answer:
      "The only Fabiszewski I could find in some kind of situation of fame was Major Stefan Fabiszewski. He was a major in the Polish army in WWI, likely not the air force...Quickly rose through ranks and even wrote. Nice little story here: (click translate upon arrival)  https://pl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stefan_Fabiszewski",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "Who is Sir Fabian z Czernina of Lesser Poland?",
    answer:
      "He helped to negotiate the Treaty of Melno in 1422, which ended the Polish-Lithuanian-Teutonic War and was a patron of the arts and sciences. He founded the Czernina Library, which was one of the largest libraries in Poland at the time.",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "What have we accomplished?",
    answer: "We've achieved several things...Let me, uh...find that...list-",
  },
];
